Edison Tang Lim

edisontanglim@yahoo.com | +1-408-797-8162

SUMMARY

Senior Product Manager with extensive experience in driving business and software product visions, in executing product concepts into elegant, lasting, and delightful solutions, and in evangelizing solutions for adoption and growth. Recognized expert and speaker at international and regional conferences. Excellent track record in building relationships, collaborating, and driving top results in cross-functional multi-vendor matrix teams. Thought leader with holistic perspectives and broad skills gained through international rotational assignments and proactive exposure to diverse initiative types. Mentor and leader who helps teams succeed and grow.

I grew up in Taiwan and the Philippines and speak fluent Mandarin Chinese, English, and Tagalog. I am passionate in learning, solving problems, enabling people, and building a better world.

Specialties: product management, strategy consulting, innovation management, systems architecture, engineering management, methodology design, and capability building.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Hewlett-Packard Company / HP Enterprise – Cincinnati, OH, USA; Toronto, ON, Canada

January 2004 - Present

Senior SAP Application (Product) Manager / Innovation and Quality Manager for P&G (January 2011 – Present)

SAP Application (Product) Manager (July 2009 – December 2010)

Responsibilities: Member of Global Supply Chain Template Design Council; research industry trends, develop business case, and drive portfolio decisions; define product area vision, positioning, strategy, architecture, and roadmap; oversee product development and adoption; team intrapreneur; lead technology and quality decisions across product areas

- Partnered with business and IT stakeholders in shaping supply chain strategy, architecture, and requirements
- Directed product development, adoption, and evolution in 60+ projects, including P&G's largest SAP projects
- Co-innovated externally with product vendors and internally across lines of business teams in global matrix environment
- Led team of technical application managers in authoring company-wide technology and quality policies, auditing vendor performance, and driving SAP development transformation that simplified developments and saved \$1.5+ millions yearly
- Started the New Idea Team that fostered frugal innovation, developed junior team members, and delivered 30+ initiatives
- Set up and led the Solution Quality Network that connected product, operation, and development organizations that resulted in an early discovery of 700+ defects in 6 product areas and a 20% reduced problem records in the first 6 months
- Mentored team members (including junior product managers); trained 200+ specialists

Strategy Management Office Lead, HP Enterprise SAP Supply Chain Practice (August 2015 – Present)

Responsibilities: Provide leadership and give direction to the newly established Strategy Management Office

- Analyzed industry and competition; advised practice direction, strategy, and business model
- Set up processes and procedures for smooth functioning of the office
- Removed roadblocks; created excitements, accountability, and reward system for innovation

Project Manager / Project Methodology Champion for P&G (January 2007 – January 2010)

Responsibilities: Lead SAP implementation projects; roll-out project implementation methodology to all project teams

- Led teams of up to 60 direct global team members through 3 full SAP project implementations
- Piloted automated testing that reduced testing time by 60%
- Led HP technical training initiative; trained 200+ technology consultants
- Co-designed and rolled out the new standardized SAP project implementation methodology

SAP Integration Architect / Technical Project Manager for P&G (October 2005 – March 2007)

Responsibilities: Align supply chain integration needs, priorities, and implementation approach with global business and IT leaders; architect P&G-Gillette global supply chain integration solution; lead technical project implementation

- Architected huge supply chain integration that supported over \$1 billion in synergy savings
- Aligned business and IT integration approach to manageable scope and timeline
- Led global cross-functional technical team of 40+ members in delivering the Gillette Integration Solution; productized the solution, which became P&G's global standard for generally integrating internal and external supply chain systems

SAP Sales and Distribution Implementation Lead / Solution Architect for P&G (January 2004 – December 2005)

Responsibilities: Lead implementation teams through 2 full SAP implementation projects

- Created solutions that automated P&G's high volume, high velocity order management processes; the solutions became P&G's globally most important sales and distribution productivity solutions
- Replaced legacy shipping and transportation solutions used in 50 North America plants

Procter & Gamble Company – Manila, Philippines; Schwalbach, Germany; Cincinnati, OH, USA

June 2002 - December 2003

SAP Sales and Distribution Systems Analyst (June 2002 – December 2003)

Responsibilities: Analyze sales and distribution processes; design, configure, and develop sales and distribution solutions; participate in SAP technology implementation projects

• Supported 4 SAP implementation projects; trained approximately 60 users and team members

EDUCATION

University of California, Berkeley, Haas School of Business – Berkeley, USA

August 2015 - Current

Master of Business Administration (MBA), EWMBA Program – Class of 2018

June 1998 - August 2002

De La Salle University – Manila, Philippines

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science, Major in Software Technology

- Summa Cum Laude
- Vice President of Academic Affairs, La Salle Computer Society

Technology and Business Courses – Massive Open Online Courses

2013 - Current

ADDITIONAL

SAP: Sales and Distribution (SD), Logistics Execution (LE), Materials Management (MM), Workflow, ALE, ECATT, BRFplus, Fiori, Personas, Solution Manager, HANA Cloud Platform

Integration Architecture: ORTEC Load Building, JDA TMS, RedPrairie/JDA WMS, Terra Forecasting, Accenture CAS

Software Development: ABAP, Java, JavaScript, HTML5, R, Android, design thinking, design pattern, refactoring

Certifications: Lean Six Sigma Green Belt, SAP Certified Application Associate - Order Fulfillment with SAP ERP 6.0 EHP5, ITIL V3 Foundation